# DINARA YAKUPOVA

MARKETING SPECIALIST: STRATEGY, WEB & DESIGN

#### CONTACT

438-886-8478

dinarayakupova@hotmail.com

Montreal, Quebec, Canada

## EXPERTISE

Marketing tools: Hubspot, Hootsuite, Mailchimp, Google Analytics, SEMrush

Design tools: Figma, Canva, Sketch, Wordpress, Squarespace, Adobe Photoshop, Lightroom

Video Editing tools: iMovie, Adobe Premiere, CapCut, InShot and others.

Project management tools: Trello, Slack, Jira, Asana

Microsoft office: Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint

Programming skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (React)-----

## EDUCATION

# College Degree in Software Development Vanier College

2022 - 2024 Montreal, QC, CA

School of Continuing Studies "Digital Marketing"

York University Toronto,

2022

Toronto, ON, CA

Bachelors Degree in Advertising and PR Moscow State University of Culture and Arts

2009 - 2014 Moscow, Russia

# LANGUAGES

English: Proficient French: Intermediate Russian: Native Belarusian: Intermediate

#### PROFILE

An experienced Marketing Specialist with 6 years of experience in coordinating 360° marketing campaigns globally. I bring a diverse skill set, including 5 years in international advertising agencies, 1 year in the industry, and also 1 year of web design and development experience. Specializing in marketing and brand communications, I've contributed to various industries including tech, banking, retail, food, entertainment, and the service sector. I was also part of the successful Airbnb launch in the EMEA market.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# Marketing manager / Web developer / UI-UX

KinoKlik, Montreal, Canada

Oct 2023 - Jan 2024

Brands/projects:

KinoKlik is a startup in the film industry that builds an app to help film directors, actors, and producers find each other on one platform, similar to social media tailored for this specific audience.

#### Duties:

- Marketing strategy development;
- · Participating in the development of Media plan;
- Working on UI/UX of the app;
- · Web design and animation;
- Coding, testing, researching, investigating and fixing a wide range of technical issues within Agile approach, following a cycle of planning, executing, and evaluating;
- · Participating in code reviews and daily SCRUM meetings.

## **Marketing Manager**

Hyproca Nutrition Co., Ltd, Moscow, Russia

Oct 2019-Oct 2020

Brands/projects:

Kabrita (baby nutrition): brand management, 360° marketing campaign:

- Brand Strategy: campaign development for baby formula 1 year+
- Online: site optimization, special projects development and supervision (from
  offline to online, social media awareness, UGC, product promotions), placement
  of articles, video development for YouTube (storyboards and production
  supervision), promotional materials preparation for webinars and livestreams.
- Offline: supervising of video production (from preproduction until colour correction of final cuts), TV placements (2 main channels), production supervision of partnership materials, placements in 10 magazines (visuals, text), retail promo-activities development

#### Duties:

- Market research, analysis of competitive activities, consumer analysis, research, target opportunities;
- Development and implementation of yearlong marketing strategy that accelerate growth of the portfolio to deliver on short and long-term goals;
- Managing fiscal budget within guidelines set by Marketing Director, including Research, Advertising and Consumer Promotion;
- Managing multiple projects: research, new product launches, special projects, site, cost savings, consumer promotions, ORM, all offline-to-online projects.
- Lead the consistent multi-channel communication to build brand experiences, connected across user journey;
- Managing all documentation, including agreements with external organizations and productions;
- Creating monthly reports for key Sales Meetings that offer insights to rally the selling organization behind the strong vision;

# DINARA YAKUPOVA

MARKETING SPECIALIST: STRATEGY, WEB & DESIGN

## CONTACT

438-886-8478

dinarayakupova@hotmail.com

Montreal, Quebec, Canada

### SKILLS

- Marketing strategy
- Market and competitive analysis
- Web design / Web development
- Photo / Video Editing
- UI-UX Design
- · Content Creation / Formatting
- Strong communication
- Project management
- Time management

# WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Client Account Manager**

TBWA \ Worldwide, Moscow, Russia

Mar 2017-Oct 2019

#### Brands/projects:

- Airbnb: brand launch on Russian market with the campaign "Don't go there, live there"
- Pernod Ricard brands: Chivas/Jameson/Ararat strategy and creative development.
- New business projects: Banking, Adidas, Service Sectors (hotels).

#### Duties:

- · Execution and quality control of marketing plans;
- Project-management of 360° marketing campaigns from budget planning to strategy & concept development, production and launch of TV, OOH and digital campaigns;
- Managing ad campaigns from strategic planning to tactical activities;
- Collaboration with Digital, SMM, BTL departments and 3rd parties;
- · Monthly reporting on integrated marketing programs;
- Dealing with all aspects of marketing campaign and communication strategy;
- Developing strong working relationships with Clients, forming the basis of trust and action to move Agency's creative proposals to make ideas alive.

## **Client Account Manager**

BBDO Group, Moscow, Russia

Jan 2016-Jan 2017

#### Brands/projects:

- Whiskas: product package upgrade development, special Projects like "World Animal Day" & "Cat day".
- Pedigree: DentaStix launch.

#### Duties:

- Project-management of ATL and digital campaigns from concept to the launch;
- Managing execution of local advertising communication that goes inline with global guidelines;
- Preparing opportunities of improvement of ad communication with global teams from New York and London;
- Establishing and managing ongoing project budgets;
- Constant tracking and knowledge of industry & brand best practices;
- Building strong, collaborative relationships with client, cultivating the sense of trust;
- Responsible for creative and client's relationship quality control.

# Junior Account Manager

McCann Worldgroup

May 2015 - Dec 2015

## Brands/projects:

 Sberbank (state-owned Russian banking and financial services company): marketing communication for mass and young audiences (TVC, KV development and digital support).

#### Duties:

- Project-management of ATL campaigns;
- Collaborating with client from concept to launch of OOH, Mobile device, TV, digital (emails, banners, landings, etc);